import { Category } from 'src/app/interfaces/category.interface';

export default {
  name: 'Глаголы',
  cards: [
    {
      question: 'to be (was/were, been)',
      answer: 'быть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to have/has (had, had)',
      answer: 'иметь'
    },
    {
      question: 'to do (did, done)',
      answer: 'делать (процесс)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to say (said, said)',
      answer: 'говорить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to go (went, gone)',
      answer: 'двигаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to get (got, got)',
      answer: 'получать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to make (made, made)',
      answer: 'делать (создавать)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to know (knew, known)',
      answer: 'знать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to think (thought, thought)',
      answer: 'думать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to take (took, taken)',
      answer: 'брать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to see (saw, seen)',
      answer: 'видеть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to come (came, come)',
      answer: 'приходить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to want',
      answer: 'хотеть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to look',
      answer: 'смотреть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to use',
      answer: 'использовать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to find (found, found)',
      answer: 'искать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to give (gave, given)',
      answer: 'давать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to tell (told, told)',
      answer: 'рассказывать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to work',
      answer: 'работать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to call',
      answer: 'звонить (по телефону)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to try (tried, tried)',
      answer: 'пробовать (пытаться)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to ask',
      answer: 'спрашивать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to need',
      answer: 'нуждаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to feel (felt, felt)',
      answer: 'чувствовать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to become (became, become)',
      answer: 'становиться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to leave (left, left)',
      answer: 'покидать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to put (put, put)',
      answer: 'класть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to mean (meant, meant)',
      answer: 'значить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to keep (kept, kept)',
      answer: 'держать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to let (let, let)',
      answer: 'позволять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to begin (began, begun)',
      answer: 'начинать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to seem (seemed, seemed)',
      answer: 'казаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to help',
      answer: 'помогать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to talk',
      answer: 'разговаривать (как занятие)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to turn',
      answer: 'поворачивать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to start',
      answer: 'начинать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to show (showed, shown)',
      answer: 'показывать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to hear (heard, heard)',
      answer: 'слышать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to play',
      answer: 'играть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to run (ran, run)',
      answer: 'бегать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to move',
      answer: 'двигать, перемещать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to like',
      answer: 'нравится'
    },
    {
      question: 'to live',
      answer: 'жить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to believe',
      answer: 'верить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to hold (held, held)',
      answer: 'держрать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to bring (brought, brought)',
      answer: 'приносить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to happen (happend, happend)',
      answer: 'происходить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to write (wrote, written)',
      answer: 'писать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to provide',
      answer: 'обеспечивать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to sit (sat, sat)',
      answer: 'сидеть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to stand (stood, stood)',
      answer: 'стоять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to lose (lost, lost)',
      answer: 'терять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to pay (paid, paid)',
      answer: 'платить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to meet (met, met)',
      answer: 'встречать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to include',
      answer: 'содержать (в чем то)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to continue',
      answer: 'продолжать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to set',
      answer: 'устанавливать (значение например)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to learn',
      answer: 'учить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to change',
      answer: 'изменять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to lead',
      answer: 'руководить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to understand (understood, understood)',
      answer: 'понимать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to watch',
      answer: 'смотреть'
    },
    {
      question: 'to follow',
      answer: 'следовать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to stop',
      answer: 'останавливаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to create',
      answer: 'создавать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to speak (spoke, spoken)',
      answer: 'говорить (процесс)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to read (read, read)',
      answer: 'читать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to allow',
      answer: 'разрешать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to add',
      answer: 'добавлять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to spend (spent, spent)',
      answer: 'тратить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to grow (grew, grown)',
      answer: 'расти, выращивать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to open',
      answer: 'открывать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to walk',
      answer: 'ходить пешком, гулять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to win',
      answer: 'побеждать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to offer',
      answer: 'предлагать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to remember',
      answer: 'помнить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to love',
      answer: 'любить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to consider',
      answer: 'рассматривать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to appear',
      answer: 'появляться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to buy (bought, bought)',
      answer: 'покупать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to wait',
      answer: 'ожидать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to serve',
      answer: 'обслуживать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to die',
      answer: 'умирать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to send (sent, sent)',
      answer: 'отправлять'
    },
    {
      question: 'to expect',
      answer: 'ожидать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to build (built, built)',
      answer: 'строить'
    },
    {
      question: 'to stay',
      answer: 'оставаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to fall (fell, fallen)',
      answer: 'падать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to cut (cut, cut)',
      answer: 'резать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to reach',
      answer: 'достигать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to kill',
      answer: 'убивать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to remain',
      answer: 'оставаться'
    },
    {
      question: 'to suggest',
      answer: 'предлагать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to raise',
      answer: 'поднимать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to pass',
      answer: 'передавать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to sell (sold, sold)',
      answer: 'продавать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to require',
      answer: 'требовать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to report',
      answer: 'докладывать'
    },
    {
      question: 'to decide',
      answer: 'решать (принимать решение)'
    },
    {
      question: 'to pull',
      answer: 'тянуть'
    },
  ]
} as Category
